README.md 2024-02-21

Pedro Manuel Ferreira Pereira, PhD -- Curriculum Vitae

Personal Profile

Age: 29; Nationality: Portuguese

I am an art, cinema, literature, and music enthusiast who studied Physics for 10 years and then transitioned his career towards Blockchain, Smart Contracts, and Software Development, a recent passion of mine. My career in Physics equipped me with a diverse set of skills beneficial for a software developer/architect, including analytical and critical thinking, proficiency in programming languages such as C, C++, Python, and knowledge of Linux and scripting.

In addition to possessing extensive experience and a natural ease in presenting and discussing my work in front of peers, a skill honed through numerous occasions during my PhD, I also had several teaching experiences, where I received positive feedback on my ability to explain complex problems and concepts in a simple manner.

My GitHub

My Physics Publications

Work Experience

2023-

Blockchain Developer at Celfocus - Hybrid, Lisbon

- Worked on Identity and Credential Management, Carbon Footprint Marketplace, and Loyalty Systems projects.
- Gained expertise in Decentralized Identifiers (DIDs), Verifiable Credentials (VCs), Hyperledger Besu, KILT, Solidity, Ethereum and EVM networks, React, Node.js, Ethers.js, Hardhat, Metamask, Truffle, and Foundry.

2021-2023

Teaching Assistant of Physics of Continuous Media at Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisbon

• Responsible for teaching classes on problem sets within the "Physics of Continuous Media" course. I won the award for the best teaching assistant of the 3rd year of the bachelor's in Physics, awarded by the students.

2019-2020

Private Tutor of High School Mathematics and Physics - Lisbon

2017-2018

Teacher of Programming and Technology at Happy Code Lumiar, Lisbon

README.md 2024-02-21

• Taught app and game development to students aged 7-16. Used Unity, C# and Java.

Academic Education

2019-2023

PhD in Theoretical Particle Physics - Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisboa

• Thesis available here

2016-2018

Master Degree in Theoretical Particle and Nuclear Physics - Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisboa

Exchange Semester in Theoretical Particle Physics at University of Amsterdam

2013-2016

Undergraduate Degree in Physics Engineering - Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisboa

Courses & Certifications

A selection of the most relevant, see full list at my Linkedin.

- 2023: Certified Quorum Developer Blockchain Council my notes.
- 2023: Ethereum and Solidity: The Complete Developer's Guide Udemy my notes.
- 2023: Full Web3 Website Course Learn Web3 with EdRoh my notes.
- 2023: Ethereum and Solidity Course CryptoZombies my notes.
- 2022-2023: Cardano Developer Course Gimbalabs my notes.
- 2022-2023: IOG Haskell Course & Haskell on Exercism IOG my notes.

Skills

Machine Learning/Al

- Fitting a model to experimental data via Loss function minimization, see this repository.
- Basic Understanding of Reinforcement Learning, see this repository.

Programming Languages

• C, C#, C++, Python, Haskell, Java, Javascript, Typescript.

Blockchain

Cardano/Plutus, Ethereum/Solidity, Polygon and EVM networks, Hardhat, Ethers, Truffle + Ganache,
Foundry, KILT, Hyperledger Besu, Hyperledger Fabric, Quorum.

Web Development

- Backend: Node.js, Express.js.
- Frontend: React, CSS, HTML.

README.md 2024-02-21

Software Miscellaneous

• Git, Jira, Markdown, CERN's ROOT, Linux, Bash Scripting, Mathematica, LaTeX, Unity, MIT App Inventor.

Languages

• Portuguese (Native), English (Fluent), Spanish (Intermediate), Italian (Beginner), French (Beginner).